Guide to the Walter Chauncey Camp Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1891 - 1925; Series II; 12.5 linear feet (30 boxes)
  - Football Investigating Committee questionnaire -high school (Camp)
    - Berkeley School - Bridgeport High School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 188)
    - Cambridge Latin School - Cutler School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 189)
    - Dearborn Morgan School, English High School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 190)
    - Germantown Academy, Groton School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 191)
    - Harry Hillman Academy, Hartford High School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 192)
    - Highland Military Academy, Hillhouse High School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 193)
    - Holbrook Military School - Hotchkiss School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 194)
    - Jarvis Hall Military Academy - Lawrenceville School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 195)
    - McCabe's University School - Mt. Herman School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 196)
    - New Britain High School, Norwich Free Academy, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 197)
    - Phillips Andover Academy - Pingry School, 1893 (Box 44, Folder 198)
    - Saint Alban's School - Saint Paul's School, 1893 (Box 45, Folder 199)
    - Siglar's Preparatory School - Salem High School, 1893 (Box 45, Folder 200)
    - University School - Westminster School, 1893 (Box 45, Folder 201)
    - William Penn Charter School, Williston Seminary, 1893 (Box 45, Folder 202)
    - Worcester Academy, Worcester High School, 1893 (Box 45, Folder 203)
  - Football: general: research notes, 1887-1922 (Box 45, Folder 204)
  - Football: general: research notes, undated (Box 45, Folder 205-207)
  - Rugby, 1906-1907 (Box 45, Folder 208)
  - Rugby, undated (Box 45, Folder 209-210)
  - Rugby: research notes, 1905-1910 (Box 45, Folder 211)
  - Rugby: research notes, undated (Box 45, Folder 212-213)
  - Baseball, 1884-1897, 1905-1922 (Box 45, Folder 214-215)
  - Baseball, undated (Box 45, Folder 216-219)
  - Baseball, undated (Box 46, Folder 220-226)
  - Baseball: research notes, 1872-1922, undated (Box 46, Folder 227)
  - Track, 1889-1924 (Box 46, Folder 228-229)
  - Track, undated (Box 46, Folder 230-237)
  - Track: Olympics, 1902-1924 (Box 47, Folder 238)
  - Track: Olympics, undated (Box 47, Folder 239-243)
  - Golf, 1870-1897, 1901-1908, 1911-1924 (Box 47, Folder 244-246)
  - Golf, undated (Box 47, Folder 247-250)
  - Golf, undated (Box 48, Folder 251-260)
  - Rowing, 1887-1910, 1913-1924 (Box 48, Folder 261-263)
  - Rowing, undated (Box 49, Folder 264-274)
  - Rowing: research notes, 1889-1919 (Box 49, Folder 275)
  - Rowing: research notes, undated (Box 49, Folder 276)
  - Basketball, undated (Box 49, Folder 277)
  - Boxing, undated (Box 50, Folder 278)
  - Cricket, undated (Box 50, Folder 279)
  - Polo, undated (Box 50, Folder 280)
  - Tennis, 1887-1924 (Box 50, Folder 281)
  - Tennis, undated (Box 50, Folder 282-285)
  - Wrestling, undated (Box 50, Folder 286)
  - Yachting, undated (Box 50, Folder 287)
  - Other sports: auto racing - trap shooting, undated (Box 50, Folder 288)
  - Other sports: research notes, undated (Box 50, Folder 289)
  - Women in sports, undated (Box 50, Folder 290)
  - Consolidated Press, 1922 September 15 - October 17 (Box 50, Folder 291-294)
  - Consolidated Press, 1922 October 18 - 1923 February 8 (Box 51, Folder 295-308)
  - Consolidated Press, 1923 April-jun (Box 51, Folder 309-313)
  - Consolidated Press, 1923 Oct, December (Box 51, Folder 314)
  - Consolidated Press, 1924 January-October (Box 51, Folder 315-319)
  - Athletics, general, 1890-1908,1911-1924 (Box 52, Folder 320-323)
  - Athletics, general, undated (Box 52, Folder 324-330)
  - Athletics, general, undated (Box 53, Folder 331-339)
  - Athletics, general: research notes, 1878-1899, 1903-1915, 1917-1921 (Box 53, Folder 340-342)
  - Athletics, general: research notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 343-348)
  - Physical fitness: Student's Army Training Corps: "A Compendium for Officers", 1917 (Box 54, Folder 349-352)
  - Physical fitness, undated (Box 54, Folder 353-359)
  - Physical fitness, undated (Box 55, Folder 360-371)
  - Physical fitness, undated (Box 56, Folder 372-376)
  - Physical fitness: "Building your Baby", 1922 (Box 56, Folder 377-385)
  - Physical fitness: research notes, 1891-1912,1917-1925 (Box 56, Folder 386-387)
  - Physical fitness: research notes, undated (Box 56, Folder 388-389)
  - Physical fitness: research notes, undated (Box 57, Folder 390-391)
  - Daily Dozen, 1918-1924 (Box 57, Folder 392)
  - Daily Dozen, undated (Box 57, Folder 393-395)
  - Daily Dozen: research notes, undated (Box 57, Folder 396)
  - Playgrounds and recreation, undated (Box 57, Folder 397-398)
  - Senior Service Corps, 1917 (Box 57, Folder 399-401)
  - Senior Service Corps: research notes, undated (Box 57, Folder 402-403)
  - Bridge, undated (Box 58, Folder 404)
  - Clocks, undated (Box 58, Folder 405)
  - Clocks: research notes, 1893-1917 (Box 58, Folder 406)
  - Hopkins Grammar School: research notes, undated (Box 58, Folder 407)
  - Yale, undated (Box 58, Folder 408-410)
  - Yale: research notes, 1892-1908, undated (Box 58, Folder 411)
  - Yale Bowl, undated (Box 58, Folder 412)
  - Advertisements for Walter Camp's books, undated (Box 58, Folder 413)
  - Reviews of Walter Camp's books, undated (Box 58, Folder 414)
  - Contracts and agreements, undated (Box 58, Folder 415)
  - Aphorisms: "Daily Dozen", undated (Box 58, Folder 416)
  - Aphorisms: "Facts not Fancies", undated (Box 58, Folder 417)
  - Aphorisms: notes: athletics, life, general, undated (Box 58, Folder 418)
  - Aphorisms: general, undated (Box 58, Folder 419-422)
  - Aphorisms: general, undated (Box 59, Folder 423-426)
  - Poetry, undated (Box 59, Folder 427-434)
  - Miscellaneous, 1914-1922 (Box 60, Folder 435)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 60, Folder 436-445)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 61, Folder 446-448)
  - Miscellaneous: research notes, undated (Box 61, Folder 449-452)
- Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1866 - 1925
  Some 20,000 newspaper and magazine clippings make up Series III. Because of the fragile condition of the newsprint, dating back to 1866, disintegration caused approximately 10 per cent to be lost in processing.
  Arranged as far as possible by years, the clippings are divided into two classifications, Athletics and General. Researchers will find a great many of these clippings undated and, in some cases, the legibility poor.
  One scrapbook of clippings on the death of Walter Camp is in Series V, Family Papers.
  After the Camp papers were microfilmed, in 1982, the newspaper and magazine clippings in this series were discarded. They are available now on reels 41-45 of the Walter Camp Papers on MICROFILM HM 137.
  - Football: History of the Game, 1876-1925 and n.d. (Box 41)
  - Football: Review of the Seasons, 1876-1896 (Box 41)
  - Football: Review of the Seasons, 1897-1913 (Box 42)
  - Football: Review of the Seasons, 1914-1924 and n.d. (Box 43)
  - Football: All-America Teams, 1889-1924 (Box 43)
  - Track: 1877-1894 (Box 43)
  - Track: 1895-1925 and n.d. (Box 44)
  - Rowing: 1866-1925 and n.d. (Box 44)
  - Yachting: 1891-1902 and n.d. (Box 44)
  - Golf: 1891-1925 and n.d. (Box 44)
  - Other Sports: 1883-1925 and n.d. (Box 44)
  - Walter Camp, Jr. (Box 44)
  - Walter Camp: death on March 14, 1925 (Box 44)
  - General: 1885-1925 and n.d. (Box 44)
    - Women in sports (Box 44)
    - Physical fitness (Box 44)
    - False arrest (1887) (Box 44)
    - Walter Camp Dinner (1892) (Box 44)
    - World War I (Box 44)
    - Senior Service Corps (Box 44)
    - Yale College (Box 44)
    - Society notes (Box 44)
  - Magazine Articles by Walter Camp: 1883-1918 (Box 44)
  - Magazine Articles by Walter Camp 1919-1925 and n.d. (Box 45)
- Photographs, [ca. 1870 - 1920; Series IV; 2 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Photographs of Walter Camp and the Camp family are at the beginning of Series IV, followed by pictures of several activities and subjects with which he was closely associated, e.g., The Daily Dozen and physical fitness. For the most part, however, the photographs concern athletics, particularly football games and players.
  - Walter Camp: undergraduate, undated (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Walter Camp, 1880s, 1900, 1918, 1920s (Box 62, Folder 2-5)
  - Walter Camp: caricature, undated (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Mrs. Walter Camp, undated (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Mr. & Mrs. Walter Camp, undated (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Walter Camp, Janet Camp Troxell, Walter Camp Jr., 1913, 1918 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Walter Camp, Jr. (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Walter Camp, III, undated (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - William Graham Sumner, undated (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Walter Camp & Football Rules Committee, undated (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Walter Camp & Guy Nickalls, undated (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Walter Camp with unidentified others, undated (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Daily Dozen, undated (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Physical fitness: U.S. Army, undated (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Physical fitness: U.S. Navy, undated (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - Physical fitness: "Walter Scamps", undated (Box 62, Folder 19)
  - Physical fitness: general, undated (Box 62, Folder 20)
  - Senior Service Corps: Walter Camp with Taft, I. Ullman and others, undated (Box 62, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 62, Folder 22)
  - Football games, undated (Box 63, Folder 23-27)
  - Football games: Yale, unidentified, undated (Box 63, Folder 28-29)
  - Football: players, undated (Box 63, Folder 30-33)
  - Football: players, Yale, undated (Box 64, Folder 34-35)
  - Football: players, miniatures, undated (Box 64, Folder 36)
  - Football: players, unidentified, undated (Box 64, Folder 37)
  - Football: practice, undated (Box 64, Folder 38-42)
  - Football: teams, undated (Box 64, Folder 43-48)
  - Football: training, undated (Box 64, Folder 49)
  - Baseball: colleges, undated (Box 65, Folder 50)
  - Baseball: professionals and others, undated (Box 65, Folder 51)
  - Golf: colleges, undated (Box 65, Folder 52)
  - Golf: positions, undated (Box 65, Folder 53-54)
  - Golf: miscellaneous, undated (Box 65, Folder 55)
  - Rowing, undated (Box 65, Folder 56-57)
  - Track, undated (Box 65, Folder 58)
  - Other sports, undated (Box 65, Folder 59)
- Family papers, 1873 - 1980; 4.5 linear feet (7 boxes)
  Papers of the Camp family include the personal correspondence of Mrs. Walter Camp and Mr. and Mrs. Walter Camp, Jr., and are filed in the first part of Series V. This is followed by a considerable amount of published material concerning Walter Camp, for the most part dealing with his life's activities and with his death.
  One final box in Series V has some correspondence of Camp's daughter, Mrs. Janet Camp Troxell, concerning, for the most part, her controversy with Tim Cohane and the book The Yale Football Story.
  - Walter Camp: biographical material, undated (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Walter Camp: notes from diary, undated (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Trips, 1899, 1907 (Box 66, Folder 3-5)
  - Mrs. Walter Camp: correspondence, 1884-1934,undated (Box 66, Folder 6-9)
  - Walter Camp, Jr. (Mr. & Mrs.), 1907-1917 (Box 66, Folder 11-14)
  - Walter Camp, Jr. (Mr. & Mrs.), 1918-1925, undated (Box 67, Folder 15-16)
  - Mrs. John C. English, 1888-1923 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Invitations, undated (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Resolutions on Camp's death, undated (Box 67, Folder 19-20)
  - Yale Memorial Gateway, 1925-1929, undated (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Memorabilia: baseball, undated (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Memorabilia: boxing, undated (Box 67, Folder 23)
  - Memorabilia: football, undated (Box 67, Folder 24)
    See also: box 71, folder 56
  - Memorabilia: golf, undated (Box 67, Folder 25)
  - Memorabilia: Olympic Games, undated (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Memorabilia: rowing, undated (Box 68, Folder 27)
  - Memorabilia: tennis, undated (Box 68, Folder 28)
  - Memorabilia: track, undated (Box 68, Folder 29)
  - Memorabilia: athletics, general, undated (Box 68, Folder 30)
  - Memorabilia: Yale, undated (Box 68, Folder 31-33)
  - Articles about Walter Camp:
    - Speeches at Football Rules Committee Meeting, 1915 February 5 (Box 68, Folder 34)
    - Yale Alumni Weekly, 1925 May 22, July 3 (Box 68, Folder 35-36)
    - Yale-Army game: program, 1925 (Box 69, Folder 37)
    - Yale-Princeton game: program, 1925 (Box 69, Folder 38)
    - Youth's Companion, 1926 September 23 (Box 69, Folder 39)
  - Dartmouth-Harvard game: program, 1926 October 23 (Box 69, Folder 40)
  - Notre Dame-Northwestern game: program, 1926 October 23 (Box 69, Folder 41)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly, 1926 November 12 (Box 69, Folder 42)
  - Yale-Harvard game: program, 1926 November 20 (Box 69, Folder 43)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly, 1926 November 26 (Box 69, Folder 44)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1951 November (Box 69, Folder 45)
  - American Heritage, 1961 October (Box 69, Folder 46)
  - Yale-Princeton game: program, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 47)
  - Yale football brochure, 1972 (Box 69, Folder 48)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1972 October (Box 69, Folder 49)
  - Harvard Magazine, 1975 November (Box 69, Folder 50)
  - Blue Football Book, 1979 (Box 69, Folder 51)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1980 June (Box 69, Folder 52)
  - Scrapbook: telegrams from friends on Camp's death, 1925 (Box 70, Folder 53)
  - Scrapbook: letters from friends on Camp's death, 1925 (Box 70, Folder 54)
  - Scrapbook: newspaper clippings on Camp's death, 1925 (Box 71, Folder 55)
  - Memorabilia: football
    - Drawing: "The Flying Dutchman", undated (Box 71, Folder 56)
  - Janet Camp Troxell: correspondence, 1928-1954, 1967-1980, undated (Box 72, Folder 57-60)
  - Janet Camp Troxell: Tim Cohane Controversy
    - Correspondence, 1950-1969, undated (Box 72, Folder 61-65)
    - Research notes, undated (Box 72, Folder 66-68)
    - The Yale Football Story by Cohane, 1951 (Box 72, Folder 69)
    - Autograph document signed by JCT, relating to "All America Team." Add 12/22/83, 1983 December 5 (Box 72, Folder 69a)
- Microfilm
  - Correspondence, Series I
    - Abbott - American Intercollegiate Football Rules Committee 1910 (Box 1)
    - American Intercollegiate Football Rules Committee 1911 - Beyer (Box 2)
    - Bible - Cavanaugh (Box 3)
    - Central Press Association - Collier's Weekly 1900 Feb (Box 4)
    - Collier's Weekly 1900 Mar - Conover (Box 5)
    - Consolidated Press - Dann (Box 6)
    - Darlington High School - Exposition Committee of the Sportsmen's Association (Box 7)
    - Eyre - Greiner (Box 8)
    - Griffith - Heffelfinger (Box 9)
    - Heineman - Irving Syndicate (Box 10)
    - Isham - McArthur (Box 11)
    - McAsham - Morgan (Box 12)
    - Morice - Page (L. C.) & Company 1899 (Box 13)
    - Page (L. C.) & Company 1900 - Rice (Box 14)
    - Rich - Shell (Box 15)
    - Sherman - Texas, University of (Box 16)
    - Thacher - Waldron (Box 17)
    - Walker - Wright, Henry P. (Box 18)
    - Wright, William Burnett, Jr. - Yale University Bicycle Association (Box 19)
    - Yale University Boat Club - Zuppke and Unidentified (Box 20)
  - Writings, Series II
    - Football: History, 1891 - 1924, n.d. (Box 21)
    - Football: History, n.d. (Box 22)
    - Football: History - Review of the Seasons, 1891-1924, n.d. (Box 23)
    - Football: Review of the Seasons, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Football: Review of the Seasons, n.d. - Football: All-America Teams, 1889-1919 (Box 25)
    - Football: All -America Teams, 1920-1924, n.d. - Football: Rules, 1883-1910 (Box 26)
    - Football: Rules, 1910-1925, n.d. - Spalding's Official Football Guides, 1891-1901 (Box 27)
    - Football: Spalding's Official Football Guides, 1902-1933 - Investigating Committee Questionnaire (Camp), Allegheny College-Princeton University (A-H) (Box 28)
    - Football: Investigating Committee Questionnaire (Camp), Princeton University (I-Z) - Rugby: Research notes, 1905-1910, undated (Box 29)
    - Rugby: Research notes, n.d. - Track: Olympics, 1902-1924, n.d. (Box 30)
    - Track: Olympics, n.d. - Rowing: 1887-1910, 1913-1924, n.d. (Box 31)
    - Rowing: Undated - Other Sports (Box 32)
    - Women in Sports - Consolidated Press (Box 33)
    - Athletics: General, 1890-1924, undated (Box 34)
    - Athletics: General, Research notes - Physical Fitness, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Physical Fitness, n.d. - Physical Fitness: Research notes, 1891-1925 (Box 36)
    - Physical Fitness: Research notes, n.d. - Clocks (Box 37)
    - Hopkins Grammar School - Poetry, n.d (Box 38)
    - Poetry, n.d. - Miscellaneous: 1914-1922 and n.d. (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. - Miscellaneous: Research notes, n.d. (Box 40)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings, Series III
    - Football: History of the Game, 1876-1925 and n.d. - Football: Review of the Seasons, 1876-1896 (Box 41)
    - Football: Review of the Seasons, 1897-1913 (Box 42)
    - Football: Review of the Seasons, 1914-1924 and n.d. - Track: 1877-1894 (Box 43)
    - Track: 1895-1925, n.d. - Magazine articles by Walter Camp: 1883-1918 (Box 44)
    - Magazine articles by Walter Camp: 1919-1925, n.d. (Box 45)
  - Photographs, Series IV (Box 46)
  - Family papers, Series V
    - Walter camp: Biographical material-Memorabilia:Athletics, general (Box 47)
    - Memorabilia: Yale-Janet Camp Troxell (Box 48)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-138
  Includes Accession 2007-M-067.
  - "Welcome Home: A Dinner to Theodore Roosevelt, June twenty-second, nineteen hundred and ten, at Sherry's New York" [personalized copy of Walter Camp], 1910 (Box 1)
  - "The Same Old Story," handwritten poem by Walter Camp presented to Mrs. George A. Adee, circa 1885; Accession 2007-M-067 (Box 1)